#### CURRICULUM VITAE OF VINU CHANDREGOWDA

### PERSONAL DETAILS

Name: Vinu Chandregowda

**Address:** 8 Griffith St, Athlone, Westmeath, N37FP86

*Tel:* +353-896024121

**Email:** vinuchandregowda@gmail.com

**LinkedIn:** https://it.linkedin.com/in/vinu-chandregowda

### SUMMARY

Experienced Maintenance & Reliability Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the higher education industry. Strong engineering professional skilled in Data analysis and visualization, RCM, RAM, CMMS, FMEA, Mechanical Handling, Draft Sight, AutoCAD, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word, and Computer-Aided Design (CAD).

I hold a valid Ireland work permit visa (Stamp 1G) and immediately available.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# RELIABILITY AND MAINTENANCE ENGINEER MONACO ENGINEERING SOLUTION - ITALY

**NOV 2018 – PRESENT** 

### Achievement/Tasks:

- Development of automatic Quarterly Report including data visualization using MS-Office based application (a series of "macros" based on MS-Excel) for KPO Kazakhstan.
- Development of Mechanical Handling study, lifting plans using Navisworks Freedom 2019, AutoCAD and RCM Study for "WHRP & CFP Project".
- Development of algorithm and schema to automate the process of filling the RCM/FMEA templates, development of quality check tool using MS Access for data integrity checks. (Samsung on behalf of ADNOC, UAE).
- Participation in the work group for the execution of the FMEA / RCM study and Maintenance Strategies for RAPID - Polymerization plants.
- Participation in the OREDA reliability data collection and preparation of reliability models for Safety Equipment (Petronas on behalf of Tecnimont, Italy).
- Development of CMMS databank (Asset, BOM, Task Lists, Maintenance Plans) in SAP ENI for ZHOR 5 (Egypt).
- · Execution of the revision of Reliability Spare Parts Study for AL-Zour LNG Import Project
- · Execution of the revision of maintenance plans and creation of man hour's database.
- Preparation of FMEA/RCM, Maintenance Strategies and development of CMMS maintenance templates for ENI WHP2 offshore platform.
- Development of algorithm and schema to automate the process of filling the Meridium templates using MS-Office based application.
- Development of CMMS databank (Asset, BOM, Task Lists, Maintenance Plans) to be loaded in SAP and Development of quality check tool using MS Access for data integrity checks for DUQM Refinery plants.
- Development of Asset Register & Preparation of HSE & B-CES (Equipment Criticality Assessment). (SNC-Lavalin on behalf of ADNOC, UAE).
- Development and subsequent updating in the following revisions of layouts related to active and passive protection systems, escape routes and signage (e.g., Fire and Safety Plans, Safety Sign Layouts) using 2D AutoCAD & Draft sight (Support for execution of other HSE studies such as

Environmental Risk Identification Report, Technical Datasheets, ALARP study. (Rosetti Marino Group/Total).

## LABORATORY TECHNICIAN – INTERN COLLEGIO S. CARLO S.R.L - ITALY

MAR 2018 - OCT 2018

### Achievement/Tasks:

- Maintained inventory of laboratory equipment and supplies.
- Assisted in setting up laboratory equipment for scientific experiments and assisted students in usage of laboratory equipment.

# ASSISTANT DESIGN ENGINEER SUNLIGHT MACHINE TOOLS PVT LTD-INDIA

AUG 2012 - JUNE 2014

### Achievement/Tasks:

- Analyzed the technical drawings and documents contributing to trouble shooting activities and supporting service dept.
- Developed 2D illustrations by collaborating closely with the material engineer to integrate and improve the quality of the products and processes.
- · Analyzed the BOM included in the design drawings and 3D modeled using Catia V5.

### **EDUCATION**

# MASTER OF SCIENCE IN MATERIAL ENGINEERING AND NANOTECHNOLOGY

OCT 2014 - APRIL 2017

POLITECNICO DI MILANO - MILAN, ITALY

**Major:** Mechanical behavior and failure of metals, metallic materials and product innovation, corrosion engineering of metals and ceramics

BACHELOR OF INDUSTRIAL AND PRODUCTION ENGINEERING MALNAD COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING - HASSAN, INDIA

**SEPT 2008 - JULY 2012** 

**Major:** Mechanical Engineering (Engineering Economics, Design of Machines, Thermodynamics, Robotics, Fluid Mechanics, CAM/CIM and Maintenance engineering)

### **KEY SKILLS**

### **TECHNICAL**

- MS Office, MS Access, MS Project
- · Catia V5, Solid Edge, AutoCAD
- · FMEA, RAM, RCM, CMMS Databank

#### **LANGUAGES**

- English Fluent/Native
- · Italian Intermediate
- Kannada Native

### **INTERESTS**

- · Maintenance in Energy sector
- Material testing, Mechanical handling, Manufacturing
- · 3D design